Contact

john.xiating@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/johnxiating (LinkedIn) johnx.co (Personal)

Top Skills

Web Development
User Interface Design
Data Analysis

Languages

Chinese (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

Certifications

React: Creating and Hosting a Full-Stack Site

Improving Your Thinking

Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End

Honors-Awards

Best Use of Tasmania Spatial Data (Runner up Govhack 2020)

Most Outstanding Tasmania Benefit (Runner up Govhack 2020)

Best Use of Tasmania Heritage Data (Winner Govhack 2020)

Uhack 2020 - Student Division (3rd Winner Uhack 2019)

John (Xiating) Cai

IT Helpdesk Support at Techbyte Solutions; Web & Software Development PASS Leader at The University of Tasmania Launceston

Summary

I would best describe myself as a tech geek, a creative thinker, someone with a positive attitude, can adapt to any given situation, able to work under pressure, have a collaborate spirit, attention to detail, and someone who takes each day as a learning experience.

I finished my masters in Information Management and Systems in 2020. This course exposed me to various aspects of each subject at different levels not just theoretically but also the chance to develop applications, manage IT projects. With the selection of app development and AR/VR for in-depth study, I got exposures to transcend technologies and well-placed to deal with ongoing, rapid changes in the IT field.

With a keen interest in project management and app development, I pursued short term courses in Project Management, UX Design and iOS Development as a plus point, to give my IT career a cherry on the cake. I joined italki Shanghai as an IT support, where I had effectively collaborated across functions (product, service, marketing, and tech team). I developed my vital technical service alongside communication skills, including distributed teamwork, rapport-building and multitasking. Apart from work with global corporations in Shanghai, I have expanded web and app development skills, gained from two years of intensive unit projects at the University of Tasmania, web developer roles and volunteer work in Australia.

Outside of the classroom, I co-founded the Multi-Cultural Club, an active university society. I started up the Virtual-studyhub project, where students can connect via microphone and webcam, to help students overcome the difficulties caused by COVID-19.

I am currently seeking a graduate position in the IT field. I have full working rights in Australia and willing to relocate to other parts of Tasmania for work. That's me in a nutshell.

Experience

Techbyte Solutions IT Help Desk Technician May 2020 - Present (8 months)

Launceston, Tasmania, Australia

- · Utilised HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap, Facebook developer tools to create a business website for Techbyte Solutions (techbyte.net.au)
- Offered IT services include Business systems, Internet services, Web conferences to businesses and individual customers with a range of technological understanding.

Multi Cultual Club (MCC) Tasmania Co-Founder August 2020 - Present (5 months) Launceston, Tasmania, Australia

- · Co-Founded Multi-Cultural Club, utilised HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, and Bootstrap to create a static, informational website (mcctas.com.au) that met the needs of the society.
- · Utilised Adobe Creative Suite to capture and edit photos, images, videos for the events recording, marketing, logo, and poster design.

University of Tasmania
1 year

Peer Assisted Study Session (PASS) Leader January 2020 - December 2020 (1 year) Launceston, Tasmania, Australia

- Designed both online and offline study sessions (Web & Software
 Development) based on the students' feedback, needs, and circumstance.
- · Facilitated study sessions by integrating learning and development skills, held online sessions for a range of different university students on MyLO.

Virtual Reality Development Unit Project February 2020 - July 2020 (6 months)

Developed the VR History Traveler - a virtual simulator that recreates historical events. Users will use the app via a VR headset, they will find themselves appearing in the middle of the Hürtgen forest in the App Demo.

Engineering Heritage Tasmania Web Developer

July 2020 - October 2020 (4 months)

Utilised the replica website of EHWA to developed enhancements to the EHTAS website apps (map tour) as discussed with the client. Created manual and video guides to assist members with ranges of technical knowledge.

Virtual Studyhub Frontend Web Developer January 2019 - October 2020 (1 year 10 months) Tasmania, Australia

Started up the Virtual-study Hub project (a virtual library study space) to help students to study online during the COVID-19 time, where students can connect via microphone and webcam, to recreate the library-like study vibe. Link to the site https://virtual-studyhub.com

italki Support Technologist July 2015 - May 2018 (2 years 11 months) Shanghai City, China

- Provided consulting and IT support for online language teachers worldwide,
 posted monthly newsletters and guides to 4000+ teachers on the platform.
- · Undertook customer satisfaction research and data analysis through the ticketing system to improve the new teacher onboarding experience and student learning experience.

Education

University of Tasmania

Master's degree, Information Technology and Systems · (2019 - 2020)

Taizhou University

Bachelor's degree, Physics Teacher Education · (2008 - 2012)